Guide to the American Left Ephemera Collection, 1875-2015 AIS.2007.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Labor, X.
  - "Steel Fights for the Nation" CIO Pamphlet, ca. 1944 (Box 23, Folder 79)
  - "Keep America at Work!" UE Pamphlet, ca. 1948 (Box 23, Folder 80)
  - "Production for Victory" IUMM & SW, ca. 1941 (Box 23, Folder 81)
  - "Cobro de Cuotas... Por el Check Off" CIO Pamphlet, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 82)
  - "Push Salaries UP!" UOPWA, ca. 1943 (Box 23, Folder 83)
  - "The People Can Win in 1944!" UE Pamphlet (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - "We Took our Fight to the People" UE-CIO Pamphlet, April 1947 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - "Resolutions Endorsed by Local Union 848" Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, & Paperhangers of America, September 1946 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - "The Secret Ballot Tells the Story" CIO Pamphlet, ca. 1944 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - "Farmer-Labor Teamwork" UE Pamphlet, ca. 1950s (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - "A Union Policy for Insurance Workers" Lewis Merrill, ca. 1938 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - "The Inflation Racketeers" UE Pamphlet, ca. 1959 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - "The Myth about the Money the Many are Supposed to Have" UE Pamphlet (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - UE Guide to Political Action: The People Can Win in 1944 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - "The Facts about High Living Costs" UE Pamphlet, June 1951 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Industrial Worker vol. 81 no. 7, July 1984 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - The Dispatcher vol. 3 no. 26-27, November 1945 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - "Support the Farmworkers, Boycott Grapes Lettuce Wine", 1970 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Council Newsletter vo. 1 special edition, February 1952 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - American Seaman vol. 2 no. 5, April 1935 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - UAW-CIO Region 6 PAC News vol. 1 no. 1, May 1954 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Union Voice, Bound Volume. 32 issues total, September 1939- August 1942 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - CIO News, vol. 8 no. 48, November 1945 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - State Labor News vol. 2 no. 40-41, February- March 1948 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. 9, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XI, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XII, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XIII, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXIII, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XVI, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XVII, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XVIII, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XIX, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XX, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXI, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXII, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXIII, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXIV, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXV, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Mine Mill Union vol. XXVI, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Labor (26 issues), Railway Union Weekly Newspaper, 1928-1944 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - American Labor Citizen, Vol. IV No. 27, August 1943 (Box 34, Folder 6a)
  - American Labor Citizen, Vol. IV No. 31 (2 copies), September 1943 (Box 34, Folder 6b)
  - American Labor Citizen, Vol. IV No. 42, December 1943 (Box 34, Folder 6c)
  - The Lansing Sentinel, Vol. I No. 45, September 1880 (Box 35, Folder 3a)
  - The Lansing Sentinel, Vol. V No. 3, November 1883 (Box 35, Folder 3b)
  - "An Essay on Labor History and the Quality of Paper" Flyer, ca. 1980 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Association for Union Democracy Mailing (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Association for Union Democracy Literature Order Form, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Brown Lung Association Letter, ca. 1980 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - "The Brown Lung Association: Fighting For the Right to Breathe" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - CIO Political Action Committee "What is PAC?" Flyer, ca. 1948 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - "What's Cooking Joe?" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - The CIO: What it is and what it does, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Coal Field Defender Vol. 3 No. 4, August 1980 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Coal Field Defender Vol. 3 No. 5, August 1980 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - "Closed Plants: Diaster for Working People and Their Communities" Pamphlet, ca. 1980 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Summary of Major Plant Closing Legislation Now Pending (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - "Celebrating the Life of Fannie Sellins A Labor Heroine" Booklet, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Fannie Sellins Newspaper Clippings, September 1989 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - "How the American Maritime Workers are Being Forced to Strike", 1946 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Public Hearing Flyer, May 1981 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Labor Committee for Safe Energy and Full Employment Letter, June 1981 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Citizen/Labor Energy Coalition Natural Gas Price Decontrol Fact Sheet, March 1981 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Rally for Safe Jobs and Clean Air Pamphlets, May 1981 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Clean Air Flyers (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - White Collar No. 413, April-May-June 1984 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - AFL-CIO News Vol. 29 No. 47, November 1984 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - AFL-CIO News Vol. 30 No. 20, May 1985 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Public Employee Press Vol. 14 No. 2, March 1985 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Local 2599 Informer Vol. 5 No. 3, March 1981 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Wayne State University Twenty-First Annual North American Labor History Conference Program, October 1999 (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - "Celebrate Labor Day!" Flyer, September 1981 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - National Labor Law Center Mailing (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Pennsylvania State University Department of Labor Studies Mailing, October 1986 (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - Western Pennsylvania Committee for Wroker Health and Safety Letter (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - "A Call to an Area-Wide Trade Union Conference on Shutdowns and Layoffs", November 1980 (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - Conference on Shutdowns Flyer, November 1980 (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Philco Company Boycott Flyer (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - "Eastern Machinists on Strike" Flyer (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - Rail Labor Rally March on Washington Flyer, April 1981 (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - AFL-CIO Organizing Institute Booklet (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - Americans for a Democratic Party Even Today Booklet, January 2001 (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - Michigan State University Faculty Associates (MSUFA), ca. 1980 (Box 37, Folder 52)
  - "No Friend of Labor" by James Morton Freeman, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Society Notes Vol. 5 No. 1, October 1982 (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Society Notes Vol. 8 No. 1 (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Society Confernece Minutes, September 26, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Society Supporter Letter, March 10, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 57)
  - "The Rights We Fight For", 1944 (Box 37, Folder 58)
  - Tipple Talk: A Newsletter of the Coal Miners Research Association, December 1980 (Box 37, Folder 59)
  - Tri-State Conference on Steel Counter Annual Report, ca. 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 60)
  - Tri-State Conference on Steel Directions, June 15, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 61)
  - Committee to Re-elect Paul Lewis Flyers, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - "Demonstrate - U.S. Steel Stockholder's Meeting" (Box 37, Folder 63)
  - "Your Dues" United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) Booklet, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 64)
  - FE-UE Flyer (Box 37, Folder 65)
  - "The People Must Act to Heal America's Wounds" Pamphet, December 2, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 66)
  - "The People Voted for Action" (Box 37, Folder 67)
  - "Monday is Now the Night to Hear...UE on the Air With Arthur Gaeth" (Box 37, Folder 68)
  - "Vets Can't Eat Medals" UE Program of Veterans (Box 37, Folder 69)
  - "Let's Come Out Fighting" by Henry A. Wallace, September 22, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 70)
  - "Your Vote Decides" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 71)
  - "What Do You Read?", July 1948 (Box 37, Folder 72)
  - "Organizing for Security" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 73)
  - "Barry Goldwater...How he Voted on Vital Issues During his Eleven Years in the Senate..." Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 74)
  - "Mill Town by Bill Cahn: A Book You Will Never Forget!" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 75)
  - UE Catalogue of Publications and Publicity Services (Box 37, Folder 76)
  - "Fighting Back with P.A.C." (Box 37, Folder 77)
  - UE Convention Proceedings, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 78)
  - "People in Action!" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 79)
  - UE Roosevelt Memorial Broadcast (Box 37, Folder 80)
  - "UE-CIO Looks at FDR" Booklet, July 1944 (Box 37, Folder 81)
  - "UE Acts Against Raiding and Dictatorship in the CIO!" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 82)
  - "Sing!" UE Seventh Convention Songbook (Box 37, Folder 83)
  - "He Had Enough! - Westinghouse IUE Leader Returns to UE" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 84)
  - "Could you call THIS 'a great union'?" (Box 37, Folder 85)
  - "Chug-Chug: A Children's Story for the Whole Feamily" UE Booklet, September 1947 (Box 37, Folder 86)
  - "UE: The Union With a Difference You Can Feel!" (Box 37, Folder 87)
  - UE Constitution and By-Laws, December 1, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 88)
  - UE Shop Steward Guide (Box 37, Folder 89)
  - "Don't Buy!" Pamphet (Box 37, Folder 90)
  - "Keep America at Work!" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 91)
  - "Defeat Anti-Labor Politicians in '54" Politcal Action Drive Booklet (Box 37, Folder 92)
  - "The Old Shell Game" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 93)
  - "Workers Need a Wage Increase" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 94)
  - "Speed-Up!" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 95)
  - "Workers Prefer UE" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 96)
  - "Side by Side..." Booklet (Box 37, Folder 97)
  - "Teamwork Among the Unions of the World" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 98)
  - "What a Good Boy Am I" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 99)
  - "Why Restore the Wagner Act?" Pamphlet, December 13, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 100)
  - "Farmer - Labor Teamwork" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 101)
  - "Profits Up, Prices Up" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 102)
  - "How UE Can Help You Win a More Secure Future!" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 103)
  - "You and Your New Job" Pamplet (Box 37, Folder 104)
  - "Your Stake in a UE Harvester Victory" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 105)
  - UE Steward Vol. 5 No. 8, August, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 106)
  - "Let's Look at the Record! Your Paid Holidays, Vacations and Overtime" (Box 37, Folder 107)
  - "UE - The Union for GE Lamp Workers!" (Box 37, Folder 108)
  - "UE - A Message From GE Workers in Conneaut to GE Workers in Providence" (Box 37, Folder 109)
  - "Frame-up! Weapon of Employers to Break Unions...." (Box 37, Folder 110)
  - "Sing Out! UE Songs for Union Folks..." (Box 37, Folder 111)
  - UE Policy Booklet, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 112)
  - "FE-UE Exposes UAW's 'Share the Misery' Plan for Harvester Workers" (Box 37, Folder 113)
  - "A Message From UE Local 601. East Pittsburgh to All Westinghouse Workers...." (Box 37, Folder 114)
  - "UE - One Union, One Contrct" Flyer (Box 37, Folder 115)
  - "Men's Business Too-" (Box 37, Folder 116)
  - "'UE Has Really Delivered the Goods!' UE For Women Workers!" (Box 37, Folder 117)
  - "An Important Message to All Westinghouse Women Workers" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 118)
  - "UE 2nd National Conference on Problems of Working House" Pamphlet, May 15-16, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 119)
  - "Third National Conference on Problems of Working Women" Booklet, May 14-15, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 120)
  - "UE Fights for Women Workers" Booklet, June 1952 (Box 37, Folder 121)
  - "UE Women Speak Out!" (Box 37, Folder 122)
  - United Mine Workers Journal Vol. XXV, No. 16, August 26, 1915 (Box 37, Folder 123)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 94th Year, No. 8, October - November 1983 (Box 37, Folder 124)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 95th Year, No. 10, October 1984 (Box 37, Folder 125)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 95th Year, No. 11, November 1984 (Box 37, Folder 126)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 95th Year, No. 12, December 1984 (Box 37, Folder 127)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 96th Year, No. 2, February 1985 (Box 37, Folder 128)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 96th Year, No. 3, March 1985 (Box 37, Folder 129)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 96th Year, No. 5, June 1985 (Box 37, Folder 130)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 96th Year, No. 6, July 1985 (Box 37, Folder 131)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 96th Year, No. 7, August 1985 (Box 37, Folder 132)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 97th Year, No. 3, March 1986 (Box 37, Folder 133)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 97th Year, No. 8, August 1986 (Box 37, Folder 134)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 98th Year, No. 7, July 1987 (Box 37, Folder 135)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 98th Year, No. 10, October 1987 (Box 37, Folder 136)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 99th Year, No. 5, May 1988 (Box 37, Folder 137)
  - United Mine Workers Journal 99th Year, No. 6, June 1988 (Box 37, Folder 138)
  - "Join us!" Worker's Education Local 189, ca. 1979 (Box 37, Folder 139)
  - Union Town: A Labor History Guide to Detroit (Box 37, Folder 140)
  - "United Steelworkers of America 1397 Rank and File, Local Issues", 1980 (Box 37, Folder 141)
  - "Brothers and Sisters of Local #1397" Flyer (Box 37, Folder 142)
  - 1397 Rank & Rile Labor Day Edition, September 1980 (Box 37, Folder 143)
  - 1397 Rank & Rile Labor Day Edition, September 1981 (Box 37, Folder 144)
  - Harrisburg Anti-Nuclear Demonstration Letter, October 17, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 145)
  - "Maine Antinuke Activists Arrested" Article, October 15, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 146)
  - National Labor Conference for Safe Energy and Full Employment, October 16, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 147)
  - Labor Committee for Safe Energy & Full Employment, April 14, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 148)
  - "Labor Groups Stress Energy Alternatives at Harrisburg Rally" Article, March 29, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 149)
  - The New York Times Three Mile Island Articles, March 29, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 150)
  - "Call to a National Labor Conference for Safe Energy & Full Employment" Flyer (Box 37, Folder 151)
  - First Labor Antinuclear March News Release, January 28, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 152)
  - Greater Harrisburg Area Labor Committee for Safe Energy & Full Employment Letter, December 28, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 153)
  - Next Meeting Labor Committee for Safe Energy and Full Employment Letters, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 154)
  - March on Harrisburg Flyer, March 28, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 155)
  - Harrisburg March and Rally Letter, January 26, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 156)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women Resolutions Approved, October 10-12, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 157)
  - March on Harrisburg Booklet, March 28, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 158)
  - Educational Conference on Safe Energy & Jobs Mailing, January 17, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 159)
  - Earl Robinson's 80h Birthday celebration program, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - UAW Convention Proceedings (2 Pieces), 1947, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - UAW Convention Proceedings (2 pieces), 1951, 1957 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - UAW Convention Proceedings, 1959 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - CIO Convention Proceedings (2 pieces), 1948-49 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Group of flyers from Hillsboro, Florida Teacher's Union (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Pamphlet, 50th anniversary United Steelworkers, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Tom Mooney Defense Envelope (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Mine MIll Book by Solski and Smaller (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Ten Hours or no Sawdust; 1969 Pamphet about 1884 lumber strike (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Union Ribbin Pittsburgh Association of Stationary Engineers, 1890 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Record from 1985 UMWA Strike (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Wages, Prices, Profits; UAW Pamphlet, 1947 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Plumb Plan League Pamphlet, 1920s (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Photo, Milk Strikers, 1931 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Strike Photo for Mechanic Education Society of America, UAW Predecessor, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - PGH Labor Day Parade, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Labor Notes Conference Schedule, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Stop Runaway Shops; Pamphlet, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - AFT Campaign Kit Election '84, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - Unionization at Pitt (15 pieces), 1980s-Present (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - Varous CIO Union Pamphlets (9 pieces) (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - Misc Pamphlets, Publications - Unions, Labor History, Plant Closings (14 pieces), 1980s (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - Division 618: Streetcar Employees Fight for a Union in Rhode Island, Scott Molloy, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - Postcard-like Advertisements for Fran Gialamas' Chronicles of American Workers II Gallery in NY (3 pieces), 1997-2000 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - UAW Solidarity: UAW Forty Years of Struggle, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - UAW 50th Anniversary Flint Sit-Down Journal, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - United Steelworkers Pamphlet, 3 Men but with One Goal, 1950s (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - Book; Capital and Communities: The Causes and Consequences of Private Disinvestment, Barry Bluestone and Bennett Harrison, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - UMWA Journal, 1915 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - United Paper Union Journal, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - unspecified
- Leftist Organizations Thought in Relation to the Rest of the World and U.S. Economics/Imperialism, XI.
  Although they organized nationally based political parties, all of the Marxist parties considered themselves internationalists rather than nationalists. The SPUSA expressed this internationalism through its affiliation with the Socialist Second International. For the CPUSA its affiliation with the Communist Third International was even more fundamental to Party identity because the Comintern functioned in part as a franchising organization. The right of revolutionary activists anywhere in the world to call themselves Communist was contingent on their willingness to follow the discipline and policies of the Comintern. Therefore, not surprisingly both the SPUSA and the CPUSA paid close attention to events in many parts of the world and frequently circulated radical publications and pamphlets from other countries. Although New left organizations did not formally affiliate with bodies like the Second and Third Internationals, because the Vietnam War and more broadly Third World Revolution fundamentally shaped the New Left, New Left publications also addressed a wide range of international concerns and global issues.
  - What are we doing in the Congo?, By Dr. Hyman Lumer, February, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - On Events in Czechoslovakia, Facts, Documents, Press Reports and Eye-Witness Accounts, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - 76 Questions and Answers on the Bolsheviks and the Soviets, By Albert Rhys Williams (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Freedom, Peace and Bread!, The Activities of the Executive Committee of the Communist International, Report by Wilhelm Pieck, October, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Capitalist Stabilization Has Ended, Thesis and Resolutions of the Twelfth Plenum of the Executive Committee of the Communist International, September, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Medical Relief Bulletin, Published by The Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - The Social and State Structure of the U.S.S.R., By V. Karpinsky, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Toward a Land of Plenty, By A.I. Mikoyan, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - The Camp of Socialism and the Camp of Capitalism, By A.I. Mikoyan, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Discurso Pronunciado En El XX Congreso Del P.C.U.S., By A.I. Mikoian, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Soviet Economy, Twelve Questions Answered By P.S. Mstislavsky, November, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - The Struggle Against Imperialist War and the Tasks of the Communists, Resolution of the VI World Congress of the Communist International July-August, 1928, March, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Turning Point in China, By Mao Tse-Tung, April, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Whence the Differences?, A Reply to Thorez and Other Comrades, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Long Live the Victory of the People's War!, In Commemoration of the 20th Anniversary of Victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance Against Japan, By Lin Pao, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Indo-China and World Peace, By Richard Walker, June, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Report on the War in Indo-China, By Nicholas Read-Collins (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - For World Peace and Freedom, A Survey of the Twenty-Five Years of Soviet International Policy, By Alexander A. Troyanovsky (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Continuous Working Week in the Soviet Union (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Marx, Engels and Lenin on Ireland, By Ralph Fox, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Japan's Drive for Conquest, By Grace Hutchins, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Terror in Kenya, The Facts Behind the Present Crisis, December, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Der Tag Begann..., Freiheit und Unabhangigkeit fur alle Volker (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - From the February Revolution to the October Revolution 1917, By A.F. Ilyin-Genevsky, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - The Next Step In Britain, America and Ireland, Speeches and Reports By Gusev, Pollitt, Troy and Pringle (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Professionals in a Soviet America, By Edward Magnus, November, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - The Telephone and Telegraph Workers, By Hy Kravif, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - This is America, By Derek Kartun, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Burning Cards and Flaming Villages", By James E. Jackson (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Soviet Impressions, After an Interval of Eighteen Years, 1932-1950, By Dr. John A. Kingsbury (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - What Russia Did for Victory, By Sergei Kournakoff, October, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Soviet Sabotage Exposed, By G.M. Krzhyzhanovsky (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Twenty-One Conditions of Admission Into the Communist International, By O. Piatnitsky, February, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Communism in Latin America, A Report on Power Politics, By Stanley Ross, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Communist Party of France Manifesto (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Les Conditions de la Grandeur Francais, January, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - L'Aggravation de la Situation Economique et Sociale et les Solutions Proposees par le Parti Communiste, January, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - La Lutte Pour la Restauration et la Renovation de la Democratie, January, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Grasp the Weapon of Culture!, By V.J. Jerome, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Do You Know Thaelmann?, By Henri Barbusse, June, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Revolutionary Crisis of 1918-1921 in Germany, England, Italy and France, By William Foster (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Anti-Fascist Italy Speaks for a Government of Peace and Freedom in Italy!, Appeal of the "Italian National Front" at the Underground Conference in Milan, December, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Second International in Dissolution, By Bela Kun (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 15 Years of the Communist International (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Our Ally The Soviet Union, By Robert Minor, January, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Socialism Marches On in the Soviet Union, By James B. Turner, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - One War To Defeat Hitler, By Robert Minor, November, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Japan Wars on the U.S.A., By Grace Hutchins, December, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - The Soviet Law On Marriage, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - The Assassination of Kirov, Proletarian Justice Versus White-Guard Terror, By M. Katz, February, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Wyndham Mortimer Meets The Soviet Auto Workers (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - 25 Years of Soviet Power, By Emelyan Yaroslavsky (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The National Question in the Soviet Union, By M. Chekalin, June, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The Red Army, June, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Russian Women in the Building of Socialism, By Anna Razumova (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - The USSR Today, 50 Years of Socialism, By George Morris, January, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - The USSR and Finland, Historical, Economic, Political Facts and Documents, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - A History of Soviet Foreign Policy, By M. Ross, December, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 31)